verseoftheday.com 2019-03-30

# Privacy Policy - Heartlight

Greetings from Heartlight® and welcome! We extend the following information to assure you, our guest, that we are concerned about and respect your privacy while visiting our websites: [HEARTLIGHT.org](https://heartlight.org/), [VerseoftheDay.com](http://verseoftheday.com/), and [AYearWithJesus.com](http://ayearwithjesus.com/).

Heartlight, Inc., will never sell, lease or rent your confidential information. We will always endeavor to take steps to assure that any information you provide to us will remain secure. We want you to feel safe in your online experience while visiting our site, so please take a moment to review the following valuable information.

#### Collection of Information

Heartlight does not collect personal information without your knowledge while you are visiting our website.

However, Heartlight allows you to provide personal information on our website. The type of information we collect directly corresponds with the service you request. For instance, you can make donations, offer your thoughts, opinions, prayers, concerns, ideas, personal experiences, questions and/or suggestions to our articles, materials, books, etc. The type of information we collect is only the information necessary to facilitate our response to your specific request such as your name and contact information.

If you make a donation, Heartlight will collect the information necessary to complete this transaction which may include your contact information and other transaction information.

If you offer your thoughts, comments, opinions, concerns, ideas, personal experience testimonies, request prayer, ask questions, etc., Heartlight collects that information and may use the information in one of the ways set forth in the following section titled "Use of Information."

#### Use of Information

Heartlight uses the information provided by you to:

  * Respond to your correspondence, questions, comments, suggestions, thoughts, opinions, prayers, concerns or ideas to fulfill a resource request.

  * Continually update, develop, design and customize the content of our website to meet the needs, interests and requests of our audience.

  * Contact you via email to confirm specific resource or information requests, confirm subscription information, inform you of new services or features, or provide information we think may be of particular interest to you.

#### Cookies Policy

##### What are cookies?

Cookies are a small text files that are stored in your web browser that allows Heartlight, Inc. or a third party to recognize you. Cookies can be used to collect, store and share bits of information about your activities across websites, including on Heartlight, Inc. website.

Heartlight Inc. uses cookies for the following purposes:

  * To enable certain functions
  * To provide analytics
  * To store your preferences
  * To enable ad delivery and behavioral advertising

Heartlight, Inc. uses both session cookies and persistent cookies.

A session cookie is used to identify a particular visit to our Website. These cookies expire after a short time, or when you close your web browser after using our Website. We use these cookies to identify you during a single browsing session, such as when you log into our Website.

A persistent cookie will remain on your devices for a set period of time specified in the cookie. We use these cookies where we need to identify you over a longer period of time. For example, we would use a persistent cookie if you asked that we keep you signed in.

##### How do third parties use cookies on the Heartlight, Inc. Website?

Third party companies like analytics companies and ad networks generally use cookies to collect user information on an anonymous basis. They may use that information to build a profile of your activities on the Heartlight, Inc. Website and other websites that you've visited. More information regarding specific uses are covered in creater detail later in this policy.

##### What are your cookies options?

If you don't like the idea of cookies or certain types of cookies, you can change your browser's settings to delete cookies that have already been set and to not accept new cookies. To learn more about how to do this, visit the help pages of your browser.

Please note, however, that if you delete cookies or do not accept them, you might not be able to use all of the features we offer, you may not be able to store your preferences, and some of our pages might not display properly.

##### Where can I find more information about cookies?

You can learn more about cookies by visiting the following third party websites:

#### Google Analytics

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google. We have implemented a feature of Google Analytics referred to as Demographics and Interest Reporting on this website.

The Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting feature allows us to collect data relating to the demographics (age and gender) and interests of visitors to the Digital Content guide website. We collect such data to analyse how visitors engage with our website. We do not collect or store personally identifiable information about visitors.

The data collected via the Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting feature is stored on Google's servers and is accessible by Google. By using this website, you consent to the processing of the data by Google as set out in Google's Privacy Policy.

You can opt out of Google Analytics if you disable or refuse the cookie (go to Ads Settings), disable JavaScript, or use the opt-out service provided by Google.

#### Disclosure/Sharing of Information

As stated above, Heartlight does not sell, rent or lease your confidential information to others. Heartlight will disclose confidential information only when required by law or in the event an entity other than Heartlight is used to fulfill your order or request. Any entity working on behalf of Heartlight is familiar with our privacy policy.

#### Ability to Edit and Delete

If you would like to correct, update, add, or delete personal information, simply let us know by email: [editor@heartlight.org](mailto:editor@heartlight.org)  
Or send request by mail to:

> Heartlight, Inc.  
> Attn: Records Compliance  
> 8229 Snow Goose Way  
> Fort Worth, TX 76118  
> USA.

We will promptly respond to your request.

#### Security

Our website's donation system uses SSL encryption to protect sensitive data transmissions from your computer to our website. You are able to see when the SSL encryption is active either by the "padlock" icon at the bottom of your browser's window or by a blue line around the window.

In certain areas, password protection is used to protect your privacy and security.

#### Changes

Heartlight reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time and requests that you review this policy for updates.

#### External Links

This website may provide links to external websites maintained by individuals or organizations external to Heartlight. Once you access information that links you to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of the website containing the information you have linked to.

#### GDPR Compliance

We recognize the importance and privacy of your personal information and data. This means that we are committed to compliance with GDPR (the General Data Protection Regulation act). This act specifically applies for all users in the European Union, but we will honor the provisions of GDPR in the way we treat your data no matter where you live.

##### _General Practices Under GDPR_

While the laws and regulations associated with GDPR are complicated, we believe you should should be aware and re-assured of several key elements of these regulations and how we will approach them. Our general privacy statement addresses many of these issues, but in addition to those statements, we want to assure you of the following:

  * Your data (personal information) will not sold, leased, or rented to another group, organization, or corporation.
  * You will not be subscribed to any of our publications without your direct request using double verification or direct request from you personally. 
  * You can request that we delete and remove your information/data from our records and we will do so upon valid request emailed to: [editor@heartlight.org](mailto:editor@heartlight.org)  
Or send request by mail to:

> Heartlight, Inc.  
> Attn: Records Compliance  
> 8229 Snow Goose Way  
> Fort Worth, TX 76118  
> USA.

  * You can request to see what information/data we have stored, and we will provide that to you appropriately. 
  * You can request changes in how we use or not use or store your information/data. 
  * If for some reason Heartlight, Inc. is no longer active as a not-for-profit organization, all information/data we have on our users will be removed and destroyed except as required by law and to provide appropriate validation of contributors’ donations to Heartlight, Inc. for the Internal Revenue Service for each of our donor’s legal deductions. 

##### _Credit Card Information_

Heartlight, Inc., does not collect donor’s credit card or bank account information on any of the Heartlight, Inc., servers. All credit card donations or bank account information is handled by either Network for Good® or PayPal®, both committed to full compliance with GDPR. Please consult their privacy and usage statements for a full explanation of their practices.

##### _Comments_

Heartlight, Inc.’s websites (heartlight.org, verseoftheday.com, and ayearwithjesus.com) have a comments section with their articles and devotionals. The comments section is a plugin feature on our site that is run by Facebook® which is clearly indicated and Heartlight, Inc. This plug-in displays comments offered by website visitors. These comments and the plug in are maintained by Facebook® and are subject to Fakebook’s usage and privacy guidelines. Facebook® has assured both its users and its plug-in users that it is in full compliance with GDPR. However, if a comment has been made by a user that they wish to have removed, Heartlight, Inc., will work to ensure that comment is deleted in a timely manner.

##### _Google Ads_

Heartlight, Inc.’s websites use Google® Ads for advertising revenue to support our organization and online publications. These ads are subject to Google’s privacy and usage policies. Google has committed to be appropriately GDPR compliant. However, information on how to prevent a user’s personal data/information being misused can be found under section “Google Analytics” above.

##### _Compassion International_

Heartlight, Inc.’s websites provide ads, have links, and run articles that discuss the sponsorship of impoverished children through Compassion International®. Heartlight, Inc., does not collect personal data/information on users and their participation with Compassion International. Compassion’s “Privacy and Conditions of Use” clearly discloses their practices of protecting that personal information/data of their users.

##### _Links to Other Resources_

Heartlight, Inc.’s websites may contain links to other online resources. We provide the links for your convenience, but we do not review, control, or monitor the privacy practices of online resources operated by others. This Privacy Statement does not apply to any other online resources where a link to this Privacy Statement does not appear. We are not responsible for the performance of sites operated by third parties or for your business dealings with them. Therefore, whenever you leave this website we recommend that you review each site's privacy practices and make your own conclusions regarding the adequacy of these practices.

#### Questions or Suggestions

Please direct all questions or comments regarding this privacy policy to Heartlight [editor@heartlight.org](mailto:editor@heartlight.org)  
Or send request by mail to:

> Heartlight, Inc.  
> Attn: Records Compliance  
> 8229 Snow Goose Way  
> Fort Worth, TX 76118  
> USA.
